

# 99

### **About me**

Full stack frontend/backend .Net developer/Sr Lead seeking challenging development environment with skills of Asp.Net Core MVC, WebApi, Angular 12,C#,VB.Net,SQL Server,SSIS,Azure,DevOps,HTML5,CSS3, JQuery,XSLT,TypeScript,Bootstrap,JLPT, NAT, Japanese



# **Prashant Khandale**

**Senior Technical** 

Lead



khandaleprashants@gmail.com



9890470946



14 years 0 month



https://www.linkedin.com/in/prashant-khandale-69a4bb28/



### **Key Skills**

Asp.Net Core Mvc

\*\*\*\*

Angular

\*\*\*\*

**WCF** 

\*\*\*\*

Japanese

\*\*\*\*

NAT

\*\*\*\*

**JLPT** 

\*\*\*\*

SQL Server

\*\*\*\*

XSLT

\*\*\*\*



### **Profile Summary**

Possesses total 14.2 Years of IT experience (June 2008 - till date). Currently working with Birlasoft Limited as a Sr. Technical Lead / Microsoft Full Stack Developer with extensive exposure technologies like (C#.Net, ASP.NET, Angular 9, ASP.NET Core MVC, VB.net, MVC 5, Web API, ADO.Net, Web services, WCF, LINQ, Entity Framework (Core), SQL Server 2000/05/08, My-SQL, Oracle 11g/PL-SQL, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, XSLT, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Ektron [CMS]), SVN, TFS, Git, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps. Onsite (Client exposure) experience of 14 months in Tokyo, Japan [Nov 2014-Jan 2016]. JLPT N3 and NAT Q4 Certified. Strong knowledge of Object-Oriented Methodologies, analytical and problem-solving abilities. Complete end-to-end project creation and implementation including Requirement Analysis, Design, Coding, Debugging, Deployments, Testing, QA co-ordination and Production Support.



### **Education**

**CS** 2008

Sinhgad College of Engineering, Pune 57.73%

12th, 2000

Maharashtra

70-74.9%

**10th**, 1997

**CBSE** 

75-79.9%



## **Work Experience**

Nov 2021 - Present

Senior Technical Lead

#### **Birlasoft Limited**

Project Name: SCMAdmin/ASCPCalendar Team Size: - Individual Contributor Contract Management Labstar, LabstarCustomerPortal, WellboreAppUser, ARCs Duration: 1 Year 2 Months Dec 2021 - Till Date Platform: ASP.NET Core MVC, Web API (Rest API) Angular 9/12, C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, LINQ, Entity Framework (Core), jQuery, Telerik Kendo Controls, SQL Server 2019, Azure Devops Description: Contract Management application is of CRUD operations on

**XML** \*\*\*\* **Bootstrap** \*\*\* **jQuery** \*\*\*\* **Typescript** \*\*\*\* **ASP.Net** \*\*\*\* LINO \*\*\* **GIT** \*\*\*\* SSIS \*\*\* **Javascript** \*\*\* CSS \*\*\*\* **HTML** \*\*\*\* **Software Development** \*\*\*\* **Full Stack Development** \*\*\*\* **Azure Devops** \*\*\*\* **Telerik Kendo** \*\*\*\*



### **Technical Skills**

HTML, JIRA, DotNetNuke (DNN), Ektron SQL Server, AGILE, SDLC, JLPT N5, NAT Q5, Q4 ASP.NET,SVN, TFS, Git, Bitbucket AJAX,XSLT, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap ADO.NET, Angular9, HTML5, CSS3, XML C#, Microsoft SQL Server 2014/2017/2019 VB.NET, My-SQL Server & Oracle 11g WCF

LINQ, WCF, LINQ, Entity Framework JQUERY, VB.NET, ADO.NET, XML Web Services C#, ASP.NET, MVC 5, Web API



**Date of Birth** 

**Personal Details** 

Suppliers, Vendor which is used by clients. This application is developed in Angular 9 with Okta Authentication and Source controls is in Azure Devops with CICD for deployments. SCMAdmin/ASCPCalendar application is for Managing the Business Units, and SRP1, Calendar managements. This application is developed in .NET Core MVC with Telerik Kendo Controls. WellboreApp Users application is for creating an Excel and PowerBI reports for all the application users Roles and Responsibilities Individual contributor/Lead for all the applications mentioned above. Attending scrum calls ceremonies (Scrum calls, Sprint Planning, Grooming, Retrospectives, and demo session) Development of enhancement stories, pear reviews and creating Pull request for deployments. Database updates, and deployment package creation Deployment through CICD Azure DevOps and Production support.

Sep 2018 - Nov 2021

Consultant

#### Atos Syntel Pvt. Ltd.

Project Name: Chart Navigator, Universal Importer Team Size: -7 (Agile) Duration: 2 Years 6 Months June 2019-nov 21 Platform: ASP.NET Core MVC, Web API (Rest API) Angular 9, C#, ASP.NET, ADO.NET, LINQ, Entity Framework (Core), jQuery, SQL Server 2019. Description: Chart Navigator aka CharNav is a health care product specially designed for coding the diagnosis ICD Codes under which member has taken the treatment, its coding Reviews by reviewers & its Audit for a record keeping purpose (Following HIPAA compliance). Chart navigator also captures the other details like Provider under which the member is treated along with its Provider types like Physician or Hospital. It also captures Membership duration, diagnosis issues, coding issues if any and many other details. Roles and Responsibilities Attending scrum calls ceremonies (Scrum calls, Sprint Planning, Grooming, Retrospectives, and demo session) Development of enhancement stories, pear reviews and creating Pull request for deployments. Database updates, and deployment package creation Deployment processes and Production support. Project Name: BizOps [Automation Team] Team Size: -7 (Agile) Duration: 9 Months Sept 2018- May 2019 Platform: .Net 4.5, C#, ASP.NET Javascript, White Framework, SQL Server 2014 Description: BizOps is a SyntBots automation team of 7 members including 1 QA resource. This automation tool is built for Health care client to automate the process of policy creation and renewal by implementing it in 5 different types of existing applications. Code is written using White framework in dot net (Windows application) and Selenium in Java (web) application. Roles and Responsibilities Understanding business requirements through Daily standup calls. Mentoring a team of 6 members in technical areas as well as process related queries Coding as per the items, Database changes. Deployments and Production support.

Jun 2014 - Sep 2018

Senior Software Engineer Hexaware technologies Ltd.

Worked at Onsite (Japan) for 2 years on Microsoft.net Technologies.

20-March-1981 Gender Male

Flat No: 503, C Wing, Jaihind Residency, Newale Vasti, Chikhali

City

Pune

Country

**Address** 

**INDIA** 

**Marital Status** 

Married

Projects details as below 1) Augmented services [Corporate/Infostore/NSAI Sites] using technologies like .Net 4.5, C#, ASP.net, Bootstrap, JQuery, SQL Server 2012, CMS [Ektron]. 2) CANVAS Project in Assurance Domain] with Team Size of 12 in Agile with technologies like MVC, SQL Server 2012/14 3) Concierge CVA API with Team Size of 2 MVC, AngularJS, ¡Query, C#.net, SQL Server 2008. 3) Kakaku.com & D600 [Internet Application] Team Size: - 3 at Japan loation C#.net, Oracle 11g/PL-SQL. Description: Kakaku.com is one of the E-commerce operating in Japan for numerous purposes like Liability insurance purchases, Property selling/buying, Transports etc. With this E-broker, client had the tie-up for getting the prospective customers to buy the non-life insurance products, by initiating the Proposals and Estimates for Bike/Car/Pet insurance purchases, which will be further gets converted to Contracts on successful completion of all the necessary processes by the Customer and Insurance company. The service which was developed as an interface between the two parties was is in the form of HTTP handler

Jun 2011 - Jun 2014

Analyst Programmer.

#### **Syntel Ltd**

First MNC company where I learned a lot technically and also on Health care and Insurance domain Application development using Microsoft.net technology over a period of 3 years tenure.

Feb 2010 - May 2011

.net Developer

#### **Opel IT Services Karve Nagar Pune**

Grabbed this excellent position with Opel IT Services where I have worked on full SDLC under genius mentorship. Worked on 5 projects with most of the projects were of individual contribution.

Nov 2009 - Jan 2010

Software Engineer Developer

#### Mechsoft Digital Technologies Pvt. Ltd. Pune

Joined as a Junior software developer on Microsoft technologies. Worked as a team member for 2 projects and also as an individual contributor.

Jun 2008 - Aug 2009

Software Developer

#### **Mastermind Solution Kothrud Pune**

Joined as a fresher in software development. Trained on Microsoft net Framework and got working experience on 3 proje with backend and frontend development.